什么都会分崩离析 对吗
Things fall apart, right?
是这样吗
Or do they?
谁还能分辨什么是真的
Who can tell anymore what's true,
威尔福德诡计是什么
what's a Wilford ruse?
于是我们紧紧抓住我们所知道的
So we hang on too tight to what we do know,
分裂为更坚固的小集团
crack ourselves into harder factions.
我们不再害怕农业区表现欠佳
We're not afraid of our Ag-Sec failing
或者生物安全
or Bio-Security anymore.
我们为威尔福德点亮红灯笼
We're lighting red lanterns for Wilford
因为我们害怕彼此
because we're afraid of each other.
而我
And me?
我在这出售仅剩的共同点
I'm out here selling the only common ground left.
我们都是人类
That we're all human beings.
我们需要爱  联系以及希望的空间
You know, who need love and connection and space for hope.
不然我们将会自相残杀
Or we'd kill each other.
为什么最近的历史
What is it about recent history
都难以记住
that's so freaking hard to remember?
永动机工程师
Well, Eternal Engineer.
他一直是社会工程师  对吗
He's always been a social engineer, hasn't he?
他必须是
He'd have to be.
他让我们都进入了他的系统
He rendered us all into his system.
尽管他的发动机或许是永恒的
And even though his Engine may be eternal,
但雪国列车剩余的部分  还是需要进食
the rest of Snowpiercer, she still runs on meat.
1034节车厢
All 1,034 cars long.
雪国列车
第二季 第八集
"永恒的工程师"
他交代了  波吉  就跟我现在跟你谈话一样
He confessed, Boki, like I'm sitting here with you.
然后他把他自制的杀人袋
And then he cinched his little homemade murder bag
缠在他喉咙上  试图把他的头冻掉
around his throat, and tried to freeze his own head off.
你喜欢这故事  对吗
You love this story, don't you?
罩着他们  车尾人罩车尾人
More cover, from a Tailie for the Tailies.
我讨厌这故事  维修员
I hate this story, Breachman.
但我不得不一直讲
But I gotta keep telling it.
我得用扬声器
I gotta get on the loudspeaker
向全车的人为车尾辩护  因为这是真的
and defend the Tail to the whole train because it's true.
不是他们动的手
They didn't do it.
你想要复仇  我懂
You want revenge. I get it.
但你得睁大双眼
But you gotta open your eyes.
我为威尔福德卖命了30年
30 years I risked my life for Wilford.
30年
30 years.
不  他不会叫人杀了他的维修员
No, he would not have his Breachmen killed.
波吉  缓一缓
Boki, take some time.
帮我们守住中间
Help us hold the middle.
很高兴我们进行了此次会面
Well, I'm glad we had this meeting,
但我们可以排除掉他了
but we can cross him off the list.
工程师
Engineer.
已经很久了
It's been eons.
她会唱歌
She can sing,
但她能打扫她的房间吗
but can she clean her room?
放尊重点
Show some respect.
她才刚回来  你到时就明白了
The woman's just got back on her horse. You'll see.
不错的延伸轨道  蒙古人
Lovely stretch of track, the Mongols.
波状起伏  高效地形
Undulating. Efficient terrain.
你泡澡太多了
You're bathing too much.
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
你泡澡的时候会思考
Well, you think when you bathe,
所以你肯定盘算着什么
so you must be up to something.
卡维尔工程师  如果我盘算着什么
Well, Engineer Cavill, if I was up to something,
你并不需要知道  对吗
you don't necessarily need to know about it, do you?
我注意到今早出现了一次缺口
I noticed that there was an intentional breach this morning.
那是雪国列车  抛弃死尸
That was Snowpiercer, jettisoning the dead.
不  不是那个
Nope, not that breach.
是在这辆列车上  在我们的冷锁区里
On this train, actually, in our cold lock.
他们可能只是在测试焊接
Well, they're probably just testing the seal.
以前没这样过
It hasn't been like this before.
四处走  我能感受到  有不能去的地方
Walking around, I can feel it. I got no-go zones.
昨晚有很多红灯笼
There were a lot of red lanterns last night.
车尾完全不能自由移动
The Tail can't move freely at all.
我们大多数人又回去了
Most of us are right back there again.
车上一半的人都被洗脑
Half the train is brainwashed.
我们失去了管道工
We've lost the Tunnelmen.
他们公开呼吁威尔福德回归
They're openly calling for Wilford's return.
尽管我抓了两个嫌疑人
Doesn't matter that I got two suspects behind bars.
人们只想相信他们想相信的
People just believe what they wanna believe.
二等厢呢
What about Second Class?
我们大多数人仍然支持你
Most of us still back you.
中产阶级会尽力守住中间
The Bourgeoisie will hold the middle long as they can.
可能这就是我们总是被坑的原因
That's probably why we always get screwed.
你们是在上一站才上车的吗
Did you all just get on at the last whistle stop?
你有司闸员  你可以放松
You've got the Brakemen, you can relax.
确定吗
You sure about that?
我看到你的一些手下
I saw some of your boys
在葬礼上比划威尔福德手势
throwing up the Wilford horns at the funeral.
那是给维修员比的  是传统
Yeah, that's for the Breachmen, it's tradition.
他们会坚守岗位  会听我的指挥
They're holding their posts. They'll follow me.
我还是不明白
Well, like, I still don't get it.
你为什么不让我就待在这里
Like, why don't you just let me stay here?
只是一阵子
It's only for a little time.
这里更安全  相信我
It's much safer here. I'm telling you.
小火球  闹什么脾气呢
Hey, Fireball, what's the fuss?
爸爸  我为什么一定要去前车
Dad, why do I have to stay uptrain?
卡莉  等事态平息了就好了
Carly, it's just until things settle down, okay?
你很快就能回来
You'll be back in no time.
这样你离学校也近一点
This way, you'll be closer to school,
不用每天来回跑穿过那么多节车厢
and you don't have to keep going back and forth through all this.
没事的  知道吗
It's all right, okay?
过来抱一个
Come here.
-我会想你的  -我也会想你
- I'm gonna miss you. - Miss you.
好了  你这样想
All right. Now, look at it this way.
你在保利那边可以调皮捣蛋
You can misbehave at the Paolis'.
但过去的路上可别逼我的司闸员用警棍对付你
Just don't make my Brakeman use his nightstick on you on the way up.
我爱你
I love you.
-希望很快会见面  -好
- See you soon. - Okay.
我爱你
I love you.
情况如何
So?
我们四分五裂
We're divided as hell.
莱顿试图维持和平  但是
Layton's trying to keep the peace, but we're--
只要有人露出挑衅的表情  我们就会爆发内战
you know, we're one dirty look away from a civil war.
人们不相信
People have a hard time believing
是罗根牧师找人杀死维修队的人的
Pastor Logan had the Breachmen killed.
你信吗
Do you?
我知道你对列车失去了信心
I know you lost your faith on this train,
但对于我们那些紧紧抓着信念的人
but for those of us holding on to it,
这事很难和解
this one's hard to reconcile.
你保持信念  记得吗  我维持和平
You keep the faith, remember? I keep the peace.
快世界末日了  宝贝  叫水管工来
The world is ending, baby! Call a plumber!
天啊  抱歉
God, I'm sorry!
水管非得在这时候出问题吗
We have to have water problems now?
你希望一整天开着自动驾驶
You hoping for all-day autopilot
美美地睡个午觉  对吧
and a nice long siesta, are you?
你盯紧水压
Don't take your eyes off the water pressure.
没问题
I'm on it.
你最好穿上长筒雨靴
You should probably take your wellies.
天啊
Oh, dear.
请让一下  安妮  发生什么事了
Excuse me. Anne, Anne, what's happened?
一开始只是我们的水龙头轻微漏水
Started off with a tiny leak in our faucet earlier,
现在所有客舱都淹水了
now all the cabins are flooding.
糟了  乘客服务部的人来了
Oh, no, here comes Hospitality.
现在该我们上场了  小莱
Okay, so this where we shine, LJ, yeah?
我们表现得好  他们就不能夺走清洁部
We do a bang-up job, they can't take Janitorial away from us.
-好  -你准备好了吗
- Mm-hmm. - Yeah, you ready?
那我们就清洁得彻底点
Let's Janitor this bitch.
你们遇到大麻烦了
Well, you're in a pickle.
我们控制住这个车厢了  沃德尔女士
Well, I think this car's in hand, Ms. Wardell.
我们已经尽快清理了
We're mopping up as fast as we can,
但有三个车厢受到影响
but there are three cars affected.
-三个  -对  小莱能搞定这个
- Three? - Yup, LJ's on top of this,
但现在附属列车里也有水
but there's water in the subtrain now,
您最好跟我来看看
so I think you better come with me.
我也这么想  走吧
I think I better. All right, go on.
-祝好运  小莱  -不用担心我
- Good luck, LJ. - Yeah, don't worry about me.
这边走
Head down this way.
我重新分布了压力
Hey, so I'm redistributing pressure,
但水压仍在不断上升
but it's still building.
哈维  出现压力波动
Javi, I'm getting a pressure surge.
等一下
Hold on.
该死  我的老天
Oh, shit! Holy mackerel!
可恶
Damn it!
太好了  你醒了
Oh, goody, you're awake.
被管子插过那里  感觉很不好受  对吧
Feels awful after a tube's been down there, doesn't it?
给
There you go.
你上次泡完黏糊糊之后  昏迷了挺久
You've been out for some time since your last goo bath.
真希望海德伍德夫妇
I do wish the Headwoods would find
能给这玩意起个更专业的名字  你说对吧
a more scientific sounding name for the stuff, don't you?
你看
Look.
几乎不疼了
It barely hurts anymore.
流泪可能会疼
Tears might hurt a bit.
眼泪里的盐分接触到新生皮肤
Salt on fresh skin.
好了
There.
你为什么要这么做
Why have you done this?
我听说你失去的那只手
I hear you've been having
一直感到幻痛
phantom pain in your missing hand.
我想迷惑你的大脑
I have a little trick I'd like to play on your mind.
这两只是你的手
These are your hands.
来吧
There you go.
不  请相信我
No, please, trust me.
注意力集中在你手上
Focus on your hands.
看着我触碰它们
Watch me touching them.
很好
Good.
你的大脑认为你还有手
You see, your brain believes there's still a hand.
混乱的神经元群分不清真假
A cluster of confused neurons couldn't make sense of it,
所以你的大脑就信以为真
so it became fixated on your pain.
什么  真的有用
What--it's working.
幻觉也有价值  如果它能带走痛苦的话
Illusion has value, if it takes the pain away.
也不算太离谱的想法  对吧
Not such a far-fetched idea, is it?
多多练习  重新组装你的大脑
Practice. Retool your brain.
会很有趣的
It'll be fun.
我们不会再给你锁门了
We won't be locking your door anymore.
欢迎来到大爱丽丝
Welcome to Big Alice.
压强过大的现象在整趟列车上随处可见
Pressure surges are popping up all over the train.
舱门的进气口关不上  所以我们承载了太多雪
Our port intake won't close, so we're taking on too much snow.
借过
Excuse me.
把水变成氢气
Convert water to hydrogen,
能分流列车上的一些水储备
its offshoot supplies water for the train,
所以当舱门被卡住关不上时
so when the gills are jammed open...
氢气太多  水如海啸
Too much hydrogen, and a tsunami of water.
没错  肯定是外面出了问题
Exactly. It has to be external.
有东西卡住了舱门
Something's jammed the gills open.
我们可以手动排出过量气体
Well, we can manually vent the excess,
但那会让我们减速  这比较严重
but that's gonna slow us down, so that's serious.
有多严重  从一到十的话
How serious, scale of one to ten?
平常我会说三
Normally, I'd call it a three.
我们派一支维修队工人手动修复即可
We'd send out a team of Breach workers to free it by hand.
但所有维修队工人都死了  除了波吉
But since all of our Breachmen are dead except Boki,
他可能拒绝修复
who might refuse to do it...
严重程度是六
Six out of ten.
我们可以当作十
We can round that up to a ten,
假设威尔福德与此有关
assuming Wilford's involved.
不是所有事都与威尔福德有关
Not everything's Wilford.
舱门确实会被卡住  这种事会发生
Our intakes do get jammed, it happens.
博斯科维奇还在哀悼
Boscovic's still grieving.
我得去让他冒险了
Gotta ask him to risk his life.
搞快点  我们没有时间了
Well, make it fast. We're gonna start losing time.
现在慢了
Now it's slowing.
是你啊
Oh, it's you.
你倒是收拾得挺利落
You clean up well.
他在哪
Where is he?
他说我该过来看看这个
He told me I should be here to see this.
看什么
To see what?
他没告诉你
Oh, he didn't tell you.
告诉我什么
Tell me what?
转身  亲爱的
Turn around, darling.
鲍勃
Bob?
等等  等等  等等
Wait, wait. Wait, wait.
等等
Wait.
-现在行了  -开门
- Now. - Open it.
他之前在干什么
What was he doing?
这很严重
This is very severe.
挺住  鲍勃
Come on, Bob.
那是什么
What is that?
维修队的老传统
An old Breachman's tradition.
你为什么派他出去
Why did you send him out there?
谢谢
Thank you.
天呐  是她
My God, it's her.
你听说她对凯文干了什么吗
Have you heard what she did to Kevin?
我们从没见过
We've never actually met.
确实  我知道你是谁
Uh--no, I know who you are.
你为什么来这里
Why are you here?
他们的能耐令人惊诧  对吧
It's amazing what they can do, isn't it?
再努努力  你就可以再次变美
A little more effort, you could be beautiful again.
我不在乎美不美
I-I don't give a shit about being beautiful.
这或许是件好事
That's probably good.
雪国列车怎么了
What's happened on Snowpiercer?
莱顿还在吗
Is Layton still standing?
苟延残喘吧  但还在
More like crawling, but yes.
你叛逃了
You've defected.
我回归了
I've returned.
我们有非常不同的旅程
We had very different journeys,
但我们都曾是雪国列车的领袖
but we were both leaders on Snowpiercer.
我们花了数年对他人负责
We spent years being responsible for others.
但现在我们在这
And now that we're here,
没有了那些累赘
without all that weight,
我不知道你怎么样  但我从没睡得这么香过
I don't know about you, but I've never slept so well.
只要你想  未来就是你的
The future is yours, if you want it.
只需看看镜子
Just look in the mirror.
我就知道你们要来了  破了那么多管子
I knew you'd be coming. All these bursting pipes.
波吉  我很抱歉
Boki, I'm sorry.
我们知道让你一个人出去不公平
We know it's not fair to ask you to go out there alone.
我知道你不想听我说
I know you don't wanna hear this from me,
但列车需要你
but the train needs you.
列车总是需要我
The train always needs me!
如果我拒绝呢
What if I say no?
那情况就不妙了
That would not be good.
过量吸气很严重
An intake's pretty serious.
我是你和深渊之间的最后一个维修队工人
The last Breachworker between you and the abyss.
听着  我不是下来给你下令的  兄弟
Look, I'm not down here giving you an order, man.
决定权在你
It's your call.
好吧
Okeydokey.
是时候去外面了
Time to go outside.
乔茜  你好
Hi, Josie.
你好
Hi.
他们给你吃了什么止痛药
What have they given you for the pain?
我准备好了
I'm ready.
我的使命已经完成了
I've served my purpose.
不不  你有更重要的使命
No, no, you have a far greater purpose
而不是成为威尔福德的武器
than being Wilford's weapon.
我同意  他是有更重要的使命
I agree, he did.
多年来移植的人造组织
Years of grafting synthetic tissue.
可怕的冻疮  和你的一样
Horrible frostbite, like yours.
我们重塑了他
We rebuilt him.
而现在  我们永远也无法发现他的全部潜力
And now, we'll never discover his full potential.
我们需要你好好休息
We need you resting.
比以往更需要
Now more than ever.
所有水压都在增加
Water pressure's building at all end points.
压力表进入红色区了
Pressure's in the red.
准备好排压
Ready to vent.
他们正在排压
They're venting.
这很正常
That's not unusual.
冷淡鲍勃是想把我们分开吗
Was Icy Bob trying to disconnect us?
他们慢下来了  为什么
They've slowed down. Why?
我的天呐  你怎么不直接去问他们
For pity's sake. Why don't you just ask them?
波吉正在穿衣
Boki is getting suited up.
只要我们释放了通风口
Once we free the intake,
我们就能逐渐提速
we'll gradually bring her back up to speed,
但这样会大大拖慢我们
but it's gonna cost us.
我估计要两个小时
I'm estimating two hours.
那两小时后我们和梅在约定地方见面
That's two hours later for our rendezvous with Mel,
我们已经和她失联了
who we have lost contact with.
保持希望
Hey, keep the faith.
雪国列车  这里是大爱丽丝  请回话
Snowpiercer, it's Big Alice, come in.
下午好  大爱丽丝
Good afternoon, Big Alice.
你也许在好奇我们为什么减速了
You're probably wondering why we've slowed.
是的  我们要来不及接梅兰妮了
Yes, we're going to be late picking up Melanie.
出什么事了
What's going on?
就是日常维护而已
Routine maintenance, actually.
我们只是在利用这条直线轨道
We're just taking advantage of the straight track.
你好啊  本  我们能帮忙吗
Well, hello, Ben. Can we be of any assistance?
不用了  谢谢
No, thank you.
我们很快就会进一步减速
We'll be slowing further shortly,
但之后会提速的
but we'll make it up after that.
那好吧  分秒必争
All right, then. Every second counts.
请帮我向莱顿先生问好
Do give my regards to Mr. Layton, won't you?
他的心情非常好
He's in an awful good mood.
波吉到冷锁处了
Boki's in cold lock.
准备行动
All right, ready to roll.
-波吉  收到了吗  -收到
- Boki, do you copy? - Copy.
他已经进入舱门  他在车顶
He's breached the hatch. He's on the roof.
等你爬上梯子  我们就减速
When you get to the ladder, we'll reduce speed.
我准备爬到侧边
Okay. I'm ready to go over the side.
他在通风口
He's at the intake.
将列车减速至55公里
Bringing her down to 55 kilometers.
我找到阻碍物了
I found the block.
这个东西怎么会在这里
How the hell did this get here?
小心  波吉
Be careful, Boki.
我够不着
I cannot reach it.
冷静
Okay, okay.
淡定点
Okay, okay, then.
波吉  怎么了
Boki, what's happening?
波吉
Boki?
我拿到了
I got it.
-他拿到了  -太好了
- He's got it. - Yes!
我要回家了
I'm coming home!
我要回家了  我要回家了
I'm coming home! I'm coming home!
-干得漂亮  -我要回家了
- Good work. - I'm coming home!
我们把他带回来吧
Let's get him back inside.
威尔福德十号  这不是意外
Number Ten Wilford. This was no accident.
-你怎么知道  -入口阶梯
- How do you know? - The access ladder.
阶梯旁的冰碎了
Ice was broken off the rungs.
有人在我之前下去过
Somebody went down before me.
我们去检查一下水平
Let's go check the levels. Okay.
这是威尔福德自己给我的
Wilford gave me this himself.
他说
He said,
维修队的人为我冒了生命危险
"Breachmen risk their lives for me.
因此
With this,
我保证也会为你们去冒生命危险
I pledge the same to you."
拿着吧
Take it.
也许有一天你可以拿这个去堵住他的嘴
Maybe you can shove it up his ass one day?
长官
Sir.
我们会在发动机服务器机房做些检测
We'll run some tests in the engine server room.
-出了什么事  -稍等一下
- What-- what's going on? - Give us a minute.
-谁...  -我把列车调至自动驾驶
- Who-- - I put the train on autopilot.
怎么回事  你的人吓到我了
Hey, what's that? Your boy's scaring me.
跟我来
Follow me.
我们把地毯拉了起来
We've pulled up the carpet
打扫了所有住所
and mopped out all the residences.
现在我们只需调高供热通风与空气调节
Now we'll just turn the HVAC on high
让它们都干掉
and let them all dry out.
你们好努力  小莱
You're trying very hard, LJ.
是的  为了威尔福德的列车
Yeah, we are. For Wilford's train.
所以不管事情如何发展  你都可以依赖我们
So however things fall, you can count on us.
不会发生什么的  小莱
Nothing's going to fall, Lj.
你只需继续好好干活就行
You just keep up the good work.
你父母会很骄傲的
Your parents would be very proud.
我可不确定
Yeah, I'm not so sure they would.
我现在有老茧了
I have calluses now.
露丝
Ruth.
你有空吗
Uh... Do you have a second?
当然
Of course.
刚刚有人问我萨姆的立场
I just got asked where Sam stands,
支持还是反对威尔福德
with or against Wilford.
他们有来问你吗
Have they knocked on your door yet?
安妮  我
Well, Anne, I--
乘客服务部必须保持中立
Hospitality has to remain neutral.
司闸员也是
So do the Brakemen.
他有吗
Is he?
这段时间很艰难  安妮
These are very difficult times, Anne.
但我相信你和萨姆
But I am sure that you and Sam
足够坚强  能挺过这关
are strong enough to pull through all of it.
我们都会应付过去
We will muddle through,
就像往常一样
just like we always do.
查克  托尼  立刻前往头等厢  小心点
Okay, Chuck, Tony, get to First Class now--carefully.
我听说威尔福德支持者可能会尝试封锁农业区
I heard the Wilfordites might try and blockade Ag-Sec.
斯坦利  马上带你的人过去
Stanley, get your squad down there right now.
你们得用食物车护送人
You're gonna have to run escort on food shuttles.
恕我直言  老大
All due respect, Boss,
但我们都没法穿过三等厢
but we can't even move through whole sections of Third.
你只能多想想办法了
Well, you're gonna have to work your way around.
用附属列车
Use the subtrain.
有个谣言
There's a rumor.
在革命中幸存下来的守卫
That the Jackboots who survived the revolution
重建了指挥部
have rebuilt a command.
什么
What?
你好啊
Well, hello.
这不是雪国列车上最美的女人吗
If it isn't the prettiest lady on Snowpiercer.
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
食堂做的三明治
Sandwiches from the mess.
-谢谢  安妮  -谢谢
- Thanks, Anne. - Thank you.
-谢谢  -你们注意安全
- Thanks. - Guys, stay safe out there.
谢谢  安妮
Thanks, Anne.
怎么了
What's up?
-这是给你的  -谢谢
- That one's for you. - Oh, thank you.
外面的局势在升温
Things are heating up out there.
我毫不怀疑你有在处理
You're on top of it, I have no doubt.
但我有自己的人脉  萨姆
But I have my own network, Sam.
从我所听到的消息来看
And what I'm getting,
反对莱顿的人多过反对他的
is there's more against Layton than there is for him now.
我不反对你的划分  但很接近
Well, I don't agree with your split, but it's close.
你知道情况可能会变得有多糟
You know how bad it can get.
我们失去了两个孩子
We lost two children.
不会再发生了
Okay, that is not happening again.
那你为什么要送我们女儿到前车去
Then why did you send our daughter uptrain?
我们以威尔福德的方式生活了七年
We lived Wilford's way for seven years.
萨姆  那时的生活更好
Sam, it was better.
如果他掌权  他会让所有人都安分的
If he's in charge, he'll set everyone straight.
-结束这一切  -以什么代价
- Put an end to all this-- - At what cost?
安妮  你知道威尔福德  好吗
Anne, you realize Wilford-- okay?
他给这辆列车专门设计了
He designed this train with portals
冻掉人们四肢的大门
to freeze people's limbs off.
看看你在要求我做什么
Look at what you're asking me.
-把你家人放在首位  -我有啊
- To put your family first. - I am.
你知道莱顿是谁吗
Do you know who Layton is, okay?
他是个好人
He's a good guy,
我都忘了好人是什么样了
and I forgot what a good guy was.
他在试图给这辆列车
He is trying to give this train,
我们女儿  我们家
our daughter, our family,
一个可以骄傲生活的世界
a world that we can be proud to live in.
如果那个世界崩塌  我...
If that world falls, I...
小莱
LJ?
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我浑身是屎  给你做晚餐
Well, I'm covered in shit and making you dinner.
你觉得我像是在干什么
What else does it look like I'm doing?
水煮蛋
Hard-boiled eggs.
-你今天表现很好  -是吗
- You were great today. - Yeah?
是啊  是啊  我就像个工人阶级动作英雄
Yeah. Yeah, I was like some working class action hero.
这是从哪来的
Where did that come from?
我不知道
I don't know,
但他们现在开始尊重我们了
but they're treating us with respect now.
谁在乎他们是否喜欢你
And who cares if they like you,
你是否能从容面对艰难境况
if you're good in a pinch, you know?
我想你是唯一一个喜欢我的人
I think you're the only person who likes me.
不  还有提尔  对吗
Well, no, there's Till, right?
她是你朋友
She's your friend.
不  我们只是经历了很多
No, we just went through a lot.
不代表我们是朋友
Doesn't make us friends.
你是我最喜欢的人
You're my favorite.
我是你最喜欢的人
I'm your favorite?
是的  怎么了  别取笑我  我想到就说了
Yeah. S-so? Don't make fun of me, it just came out.
没有  小奥
No, Oz, um--
你也是我最喜欢的人
You're my favorite too.
蠢货
Dumbass.
这是发动机机房
This is the Engine server room.
发动机仍然没有全力运行
The Engine still isn't running at full capacity,
但是与此同时在自动调节
but it's self-regulating as we speak by that,
发动机的大脑
the Engine's brain.
威尔福德工业数字自动系统
Wilford Industries digital automation system,
每秒发送和接收上千条信息
sending and receiving thousands of messages per second.
我们的氢输入信号一直在波动
Our hydrogen input signal keeps fluctuating.
你诊断的是性能评价模型  不是那个
You ran diagnostics on the PEMs, it's not that.
天  那些数字好低
Jesus, those numbers are low.
一秒前还过高
A second ago they were too high.
我能听到你的仓鼠在他们的轮胎上跑
I can hear your hamsters, running on their wheel.
冷淡鲍勃一直到了他们的火车头
Icy Bob made it all the way to the Engine.
他对他们的通风口做了些什么
He did something to their intake.
所以他们才在排压
That's why they were venting.
太棒了  我就知道她能想明白
Well done. I knew she'd get it.
只是晚了两步而已
And only two steps behind.
拜托
Come on.
是放大误差
It's an amplification error.
H1感应器  在通风口里
The H1 sensor. It's in the intake.
道钉肯定碰到了它
The rail spike must've made contact with it,
-可能造成了超负荷  -该死
- could've caused on overload. - Shit.
烧焦了
It's fried.
当然
Of course.
感应器发动不起来肯定损坏了传递
The sensor misfiring must've damaged the relay.
造成控制系统超负荷
It caused control systems to overload.
本  我们没法修  只能替换
Ben, we can't repair. We need to replace it.
我猜肯定不容易
I'm guessing that's not easy.
这是谐波模块
This is the Harmonic Module.
威尔福德的上帝模块
Wilfred's God Module.
它负责制氢
It's responsible for hydrogen production,
而氢给发动机提供动力
which powers the Engine.
如果这玩意出故障
If this thing is malfunctioning,
整个发动机都会垮掉
the entire Engine will collapse.
其实替换很容易
It's relatively easy to replace.
只是我们没有多余的
We just don't have another one.
我想我知道谁有
I bet I know who does.
他们修好了他们的通风口
They fixed their intake.
你肯定知道他们可以
You must have known that they could.
他们回到了正常速度  所以现在怎么办
They're back at normal speed, so what now?
应该先打个电话吧
I imagine it would start with a phone call, hmm?
来了
Oh, here it is.
大爱丽丝
Big Alice, Big Alice.
我们有紧急状况
We have an emergency.
太棒了  亲爱的  真棒
Splendid, Darling. Bravo.
你开始明白了  对吗
You're starting to see it now, aren't you?
你是说激增的水线
You mean to say that exploding waterlines
是威尔福德干的
are Wilford's doing?
他故意造成了这个危机
He caused this crisis on purpose?
这正是我想说的
That is exactly what I mean to say, yes.
他在破坏他自己的发动机
He's sabotaging his own Engine?
无所谓是不是他造成的
Doesn't matter that he caused it.
他是我们唯一的出路  我们知道  他也知道
He is our only way out. We know it, so does he.
威尔福德有替换的上帝模块
Wilford has a replacement God Module,
但我们必须让他一起过来
but he comes with it.
我们有大约两小时时间
We have about two hours
来让我们的发动机系统重新上线
to get our Engine systems back online.
没有威尔福德的帮助
Without Wilford's help,
明早前我们就都将玩完
it's the end of all of us by morning.
好吧  要是他的支持者发现
Okay, so what happens when his supporters find out
他在火车头力挽狂澜怎么办
that he's in the Engine saving the day?
我打赌  会传出去的
Sparks will fly, Guarantee it.
不能让人发现  我们可以控制住他
Nobody finds out. We can contain him.
他同意一个人来
He agreed to come alone,
所以我们把路线清空  偷偷带他过来
so we clear the route and bring him up secretly.
我们确保没人知道他来过
We'll make sure no one will ever know he was here.
然后他会做什么
And then what will he do?
安德烈  你要让他进火车头
Andre, you're letting him in the Engine.
听着  我们都知道威尔福德疯到
Look, we all know that Wilford is crazy enough
愿意赌上一切
to gamble everything:
梅兰妮的回归
our return to Melanie,
两辆列车  生命的未来
both trains, the future of life as we know it.
但我们没有别的选择
But we don't have another choice,
我需要你们都同意
and I need you all to get onboard.
我会全程盯着威尔福德
I'll have eyes on Wilford the entire time.
如果出了差错呢
And what if it all goes to shit?
如果出了差错  你会知道的
If it all goes to shit, you'll know.
我会发射闪光信号
I'll send up a flare.
我们得走了
We have to go.
罗切  露丝
Roche, Ruth.
这里好安静
Awfully quiet in here.
我一定很受欢迎
I must be quite popular
你们都不想让任何人见到我
if you don't want anyone to see me.
我们会带你去前车
We're taking you uptrain.
你替换零件的时候
You'll be watched carefully
我们会盯着你
while you replace the part.
这边请  威尔福德先生
Right this way, Mr. Wilford.
真遗憾没人来
Pity there's no one here to
见证这历史性的一刻  对吗  罗切
witness this historic occasion, eh, Roche?
-坐好了吗  -好了
- You in? - We're in.
原谅我  我很多愁善感
Forgive me, I'm sentimental.
本
Ben.
像往常一样又来破坏气氛了
Here to ruin the moment as per usual.
你先请  威尔福德先生
After you, Mr. Wilford.
谢谢  莱顿先生
Why, thank you, Mr. Layton.
我们要在此道别了
Ah, this is where we leave you.
那就下次见  露丝
Until we meet again, then, Ruth.
罗切
And Roche,
你用智慧和沉着维持住了权力的平衡
you hold the balance of power with wisdom and aplomb.
希望这能持续下去
I hope that lasts.
你好  老姑娘
Hello, old girl.
-哈维尔  -威尔福德先生
- Javier. - Mr. Wilford.
我听说了一个关于你的有趣故事
I heard a funny story about you.
梅兰妮偷走列车的时候
Is it true you were in the bathroom
你是不是在厕所里
when Melanie stole the train?
是的  正在大便
Caught with my pants down, yes, sir.
请交出行李箱
Briefcase, please.
我拿给哈维  我喜欢他
I-I'll give it to Javi. I like him.
你要换掉连接
You'll want to replace the ribbon
H1感应器的带子
connecting it to the H1 sensor.
你可以从这观看
Hey, you can watch from here.
威尔福德上了雪国列车  我亲眼看到的
Wilford's on Snowpiercer. I saw him myself.
-他应该在火车头里  -那就让他待在那
- We think he's in the Engine. - So let's keep him there.
我们跟车尾军的人数几乎不相上下了
We nearly match the Tail army's numbers.
人们想要我们站出来  现在是我们的机会
People want us to step up. Now's our chance.
没有我  你们的发动机不到一小时就会挂掉
Without me, your Engine would die on you in less than an hour.
你为了作秀愿意冒险跑这么远
You risked taking it this far for a publicity stunt.
不  是为了看老朋友
No, to see old friends.
为了再次看到你  好久没见了
To see you again. It's been too long.
我太惹眼  没法保密
I'm too big to keep secret.
迟早他们会知道我来过这里力挽狂澜
Sooner or later, they'll know I was here, saving the day.
确保重置通风口感应器
Make sure you reset the Intake Sensor.
-已经重置了  -他们能应付
- Already have. - I think they got it.
-你怎么知道  -各位  能专心点吗
- How would you know? - Guys, can we focus, please?
模块已连上
Module's connected.
准备重新校准处理器
Ready to recalibrate CPU.
准备提供动力
Ready to power.
系统看着不错  上线了
All right, systems look good. It's online.
处理输入数据中
Processing input--
见鬼  见鬼  超负荷了
Shit, shit, shit, shit, it's overloading!
断开  断开
Disconnect it! Disconnect it!
你对我的火车头做了什么
What the hell have you done to my Engine?
梅兰妮在第五圈的时候
Melanie retrofitted the bogie motor circuitry
改进了转向架马达电路
during our fifth revolution.
为了覆盖自动化
To override automation.
因为梅兰妮的入侵
Because of Melanie's hack,
我的上帝模块不能覆盖系统
my God Module can't override the system.
所有制氢都停止了
All hydrogen production is suspended.
要不了多久整个火车头都会挂掉
We have minutes before the entire Engine will fail!
我们让你进了火车头
We let you in the Engine.
解决它
Fix it.
各位  只剩14%了
Guys, guys, we're down to 14%.
我们不能断开梅兰妮的改进吗
What, we can't just disconnect Melanie's hack?
不行  它连上了转向架马达
No, no, no, it's connected to the bogie motors.
我们没有足够的储备能源重启
We don't have the energy reserves to restart them.
大爱丽丝
Big Alice.
大爱丽丝可以推进
Big Alice can push.
我们手动断开转向架马达
We'll manually disengage the bogie motors
这样她就能在较少的阻力下推进了
so she can push with less resistance,
启动紧急关闭
do an emergency shutdown.
-关掉发动机  -是的
- Shut down the Engine? - Yes.
换上新电路  趁我们还有足够的速度
Rewire the circuitry and jump-start her
用跨接引线启动
while we still have enough speed.
那得手动关掉200个
That's over 200 manual shutdowns.
而且我们都不能确定它能不能再恢复
And we don't even know if it'll start back up again.
我去办
I'm on it.
雪国列车  雪国列车
Snowpiercer, Snowpiercer.
-这是五级紧急状况  -我们走
- This is a level 5 emergency. - Damn, let's go!
-五级  -快走  五级
- It's level 5! - Move, level 5!
快走  快走
Let's move, move, move!
-快  -快点  快点
- Come on! - Let's go, let's go!
这是手动重启程序
This is a Manual Restart protocol.
重启  重复  重启  重启
Restart. I repeat, restart, restart.
让开  别挡道
Move, get out of the way.
发生了什么
What the hell's happened?
手动重启  从来没有过
A manual restart? That's never been done before.
你有听到安德烈的消息吗
Have you heard anything from Andre?
没有
No.
传言威尔福德在前车
Word got out Wilford is uptrain.
他的支持者想要把他留在这儿
His supporters are mobilizing to keep him here.
大爱丽丝  你听到我的话了吗
Big Alice, did you hear what I said?
听到  你要关掉雪国列车
Yes, you're powering down Snowpiercer.
全部吗
All of her?
-这是你计划的一部分吗  -不是
- Is this a part of your plan? - No!
当我们解开转向架时  我们需要你推进
When we disengage the bogies, we need you to push.
我们不能低于终端  不然就无法用跨接引线启动
We can't go below terminal, or the jump-start won't work.
还有三分钟就要到临界值了
We'll only have three minutes before we hit critical.
已经不到了
Just under.
好
Okay.
好  我试试  我会推进
Okay, I'll try, I'll push.
启动三级关闭
Engage level 3 shutdown.
断开氢气压缩机
Disengaging hydrogen compressors.
限制氢电解
Restricting hydrogen electrolysis.
雪国列车  雪国列车
Snowpiercer, Snowpiercer,
马上开始手动关闭  五  四
start manual shutdown in five, four,
三  二  一
three, two, one.
好安静
So quiet.
-准备好了吗  哈维尔  -快了
- You about ready, Javier? - Almost.
可以了  哈维
You're good, Javi.
别管了  这里只有你和我
Just tune it all out. It's just me and you here.
怎么这么慢
Come on, what's the holdup?
把握机会  哈维
Seize the moment, Javi.
你太慢了
You're too slow.
你能做吗  莱顿  不  你不是工程师
Can you do it, Layton? No, you're not an Engineer.
你怎么能领导这列车
How can you expect to lead this train?
你都不懂它是怎么运行的
You don't even understand how it works.
好了
There.
雪国列车  我是首席工程师威尔福德
Snowpiercer, this is Head Engineer Wilford.
-他在这  -是他吗
- He's here. - Is that him?
是时候结束这荒诞闹剧了
Enough of this nonsense.
是威尔福德
It's Wilford!
工程师和轨道工  如果你们已就位
Engineers and Tunnelmen, if you are on your marks,
等我指令手动重启发动机
wait for my command to restart the Engine manually.
哈维尔  你准备好了吗
Javier, you about ready?
发动机准备好手动重启了
Engine ready for manual restart.
很好  很好
Good, good, good.
一个接一个的游戏
Games upon games.
交响乐队里只有一个指挥
There's only one conductor of the orchestra.
雪国列车  立刻重启系统
Snowpiercer, restart systems now.
准备控制
Back and ready to take control.
一二三四五六七八九十
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten.
敬威尔福德
To Wilford!
冲啊  威尔福德
Go, Wilford, go!
威尔福德
Wilford! Whoo!
威尔福德  威尔福德  威尔福德  威尔福德
Wilford! Wilford! Wilford! Wilford!
威尔福德  威尔福德  威尔福德
Wilford! Wilford! Wilford!
闪光信号
他们要带你去大爱丽丝
They're taking you to Big Alice.
他保证不会亏待你
He promised you'll be well treated.
我幸存过一次
I survived that once.
我答应要给车尾人自由
I promised the Tailies their freedom.
跟他们说我会保护他们
Told them that I would protect them.
我会竭尽全力帮助车尾
I will do what I can to help the Tail.
我只想看到我的孩子出生
I just wanna see my kid be born, you know?
也许有一天能认识他们
Maybe get to know them one day.
你还好吗
You okay?
你有一分钟
You got one minute.
我
I--
抱歉  扎拉
hey, I'm so sorry, Zarah.
安德烈
Andre.
这辆列车不停想要搞垮我们
This train just keeps trying to take us down.
但从没成功
But it never has.
你不能放弃
You don't give up.
明白吗
You understand me?
我们永不言弃
We don't give up.
-祝你好运  -你也是  罗切
- Good luck. - You too, Roche.
你要去大爱丽丝跟威尔福德报告
You're to report to Wilford on Big Alice.
明白
Got it.
你护送我
You're my escort?
是的  你做了正确的选择
Yes. You made the right decision.
约瑟夫在楼上
Joseph's upstairs.
我给你带路
I'll show you the way.
来
Come.
威尔福德先生
Mr. Wilford.
列车交给你了
You have the train.